Register of the Victor Gilinsky Papers, 1943-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
- PERSONAL NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION OFFICE FILES, 1974-1984
  - Correspondence. Alphabetical
    - Imai, Ryukichi, 1975. Correspondence (Folder 9)
    - Jenkins, Brian (Rand Corp.), 1975-1983. Letter and reports relating to terrorism (Folder 10-12)
    - Kestin, Joseph, 1982-1984. Letters (Folder 13)
    - Kolkowicz, Roman, 1975-1979. Includes mimeographed report relating to nuclear proliferation (Folder 14)
    - Lanouette, William, 1983. Letters and articles (Folder 15)
    - Leon, Masha, 1979. Letters and articles (Folder 16)
    - Levine, Meldon E., 1979. Letter (Folder 17)
    - Levine, Robert, 1979. Letter and report on Three Mile Island (TMI) (Folder 18)
    - Lujan, Manuel, Jr. (Rep.), 1979. Letter (Folder 19)
    - Marshall, Walter, 1979. Letter (Folder 20)
    - Mathias, Charles McC., Jr. (Senator), 1980-1981. Letters (Folder 21)
    - McKitterick, Nathaniel M., 1979. Letter (Folder 22)
    - Miller, C.O., 1979. Letter and reports (Folder 23)
    - Morgan, Robert (Rep.), 1978. Relates to the Perkins plant in North Carolina (Folder 24)
    - Neal, Stephen (Rep.), 1979. Correspondence (Box 10., Folder 1)
    - Pickering, Thomas, 1979-1981. Letter and report (Folder 2)
    - Rand Corporation, 1975-1982 (Folder 3)
    - Rickover, Hyman G., 1979-1983. Includes testimony transcripts, memoranda, and miscellany (Folder 4-6)
    - Rhodes, Joseph, Jr., 1980. Correspondence (Folder 7)
    - Roisman, Anthony (NRDC), 1976-1979. Letters and report (Folder 8)
    - Rowen, Henry S., 1980-1981. Letters and report (Folder 9)
    - Schleede, Glenn (OMB), 1977-1983. Includes statements by President Ford (Folder 10)
    - Shaker, Mohamed, 1979. Letter and articles (Folder 11)
    - Simon, Paul (Rep.), 1980-1982. Letters (Folder 12)
    - Simpson, Alan K. (Senator), 1980. Letter (Folder 13)
    - Smith, Gerard, 1977-1979. Letters (Folder 14)
    - Sokolski, Henry, 1980-1983. Letters and reports relating to non-proliferation issues (Folder 15-17)
    - Spector, Leonard S., 1979. Speech transcript and article with cover letter (Folder 18)
    - Starr, Chauncey, 1978-1979. Letter and speech transcripts relating to the Civex fuel reprocessing process (Box 11., Folder 1)
    - Swidler, Joseph, 1977-1981. Letter, memorandum and speech transcript (Folder 2)
    - Taylor, Vince, 1976-1979. Letters and reports relating to the fuel cycle (Folder 3-6)
    - Tsongas, Paul (Senator), 1979. Letters and memoranda (Folder 7)
    - Tyrrell, R. Emmett, Jr., 1981. Correspondence (Folder 8)
    - Udall, Morris K. (Rep.), 1976-1983. Letters, speech transcripts and notes (Folder 9-10)
    - Wade, Nicholas, 1983. Letter (Folder 11)
    - Weiher, Rodney, 1976-1978. Memorandum and reports with cover letter (Folder 12)
    - Willrich, Mason, 1975-1983. Includes reports and statements (Folder 13-14)
  - Correspondence. Chronological, 1974 Dec.-1984 June. NOTE: includes correspondence with many of the individuals listed above
    - General. Miscellaneous, 1974-1984 (Box 12., Folder 1-5)
    - 1975 Jan.-Oct. (Folder 6-9)
    - 1975 Nov.-1976 Dec. (Box 13., Folder 1-9)
    - 1977 Jan.-Dec. (Box 14., Folder 1-10)
    - 1978 Jan.-Dec. (Box 15., Folder 1-9)
    - 1979 Jan.-Oct. (Box 16., Folder 1-10)
    - 1979 Nov.-1980 April (Box 17., Folder 1-6)
    - 1980 April-Sept. (Box 18., Folder 1-6)
    - 1980 Oct.-1981 May (Box 19., Folder 1-8)
    - 1981 June-Dec. (Box 20., Folder 1-7)
    - 1982 Jan.-Nov. (Box 21., Folder 1-9)
    - 1982 Dec.-1983 June (Box 22., Folder 1-7)
    - 1983 July-Dec. (Box 23., Folder 1-6)
    - 1984 Jan.-June (Box 24., Folder 1-6)
- GENERAL NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION OFFICE FILES, 1972-1984
  - General
    - Administrative functions
      - Atomic Energy Commission material, 1972 (Box 25., Folder 1)
      - Energy Reorganization Act of 1974. Relates to the establishment of the NRC (Folder 2)
      - Organizational structure, 1974-1984
        - Commissioners
          - General, 1977 July-1984 April. Relates to the role of the Commissioners in agency proceedings and adjudications, procedural matters, the power of the Chairman, and other miscellaneous subjects (Folder 3)
          - Anders, William A. Memorandum, 1975 (Folder 4)
          - Asselstine, James K. Speech transcripts and memoranda, 1982-1984 (Folder 5)
          - Bradford, Peter A. Correspondence and speech transcripts, 1977-1983 (Folder 6)
          - Hendrie, Joseph M. Clipping, speech transcripts and a letter, 1977-1980 (Folder 7)
          - Kennedy, Richard T. Letters, speeches, report, memoranda, 1977-1981 (Folder 8)
          - Palladino, Nunzio J.
            - General. Press release and memoranda, 1981-1983 (Folder 9)
            - Speech transcripts, 1981-1983 (Folder 10-11)
          - Roberts, Thomas M. Memoranda, speeches, curriculum vitae, 1981-1982 (Folder 12)
          - Rowden, Marcus A. Speech transcript and memoranda, 1977-1979 (Folder 13)
        - Staff
          - General, 1981 Feb.-1984 May. Relates to the staff role in agency proceedings, and communications between the Commission and the staff. Also includes a memorandum relating to a proposed visit by Dr. Gilinsky to the Region I office. (Folder 14)
          - Senior Executive Service program. Includes a report by D.A.M.A.N.S. and Assoc. entitled, "Final Report: Audit of Supergrade Positions at the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission," and an inquiry from Rep. Markey as to procedures used to determine bonuses and awards, 1977 Dec.-1984 Jan. (Box 26., Folder 1-4)
      - Reorganization Plan. Response to recommendations of the President's Commission on Three Mile Island (Kemeny Commission)
        - General
          - 1979 Nov.-Dec. Includes a memorandum for Rep. Udall, 1979 Dec. 20 (Folder 5-7)
          - 1980 Jan.-April. Hearings, 1980 April 17-18 (Box 27., Folder 1-7)
          - 1980 April-July. Hearings, April 29 and May 6 (Box 28., Folder 1-7)
          - 1980 July-1981 June. NRC report on implications of Reorganization Plan, 1980 July-Aug. (Box 29., Folder 1-6)
        - Exports, 1980 Jan.-1982 Jan. (Folder 7-8)
        - Regionalization, 1982 Sept.-1984 March (Box 30., Folder 1-4)
    - Fiscal functions
      - General, 1981-1983. Relates to a telephone system contract and a financial management information system (IFMIS). (Folder 5)
      - Budgets. NOTE: Many of the budget hearings also cover a variety of other issues, such as quality assurance, licensing, Three Mile Island, etc.
        - FY 1976. Amendment to strengthen the role of the Chairman, 1975 March-Aug. (Folder 6-7)
        - FY 1980. Supplemental budget request, 1980 Feb. Bevill Committee hearing, Feb. 13. Notebook and transcript (Folder 8-9)
        - FY 1981
          - 1980 Feb. 22 Dingell Committee hearing. Transcripts (Box 31., Folder 1-2)
          - 1980 Feb. 26. Bevill Committee hearing. Transcript (Folder 3)
          - 1980 Feb. 27. Bevill Committee hearing. Transcript (Folder 4)
          - 1980 Feb. 28. Hart/Simpson Committee hearing. Transcript (Folder 5)
          - 1980 Feb.-March. Udall Committee hearing, March 7 (Folder 6)
            - Notebook (Folder 7-9)
            - Transcript (Box 32., Folder 1)
          - 1980 March 24. Hart/Simpson Committee hearing. Transcript (Folder 2)
          - 1980 April 17. Bevill Committee hearing. Transcript (Folder 3)
          - 1981 April 27-June 4. Supplemental budget request (Folder 4-5)
        - FY 1982
          - 1981 Feb. 19. Bevill Committee hearing (Folder 6-7)
            - General, 1980 Dec.-1981 March (Folder 8)
            - Transcript
          - 1981 Feb. 24. Udall Committee hearing
            - General, 1981 Jan.-March (Box 33., Folder 1-3)
            - Transcript (Folder 4)
          - 1981 Feb. 26. Hart/Simpson Committee hearing
            - General, Feb. 26-March 12 (Folder 5)
            - Follow-up questions, April 9. Drafts and final copies (Folder 6-7)
            - Transcript (Box 34., Folder 1)
          - 1981 March-April. Hatfield Committee hearings, March 16-April 24 (Folder 2-4)
          - 1981 March 30. Ottinger/Markey Committee hearing
            - General, March-April (Folder 5)
            - Follow-up questions, March 30 (Folder 6)
            - Transcript (Folder 7)
          - 1981 April 2. Bevill Committee hearing
            - General, March 31-April 8 (Box 35., Folder 1)
            - Follow-up questions (Folder 2-4)
            - Transcript (Folder 5)
          - 1981 May 12-18. Ottinger/Markey Committee, Broyhill amendments to authorization bill (Folder 6)
        - FY 1983
          - General
            - 1981 Dec.-1982 April (Folder 7-9)
            - 1982 June-1983 Feb. (Box 36., Folder 1-2)
          - 1982 Feb. 22. Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works
            - General, Feb. 1-March 24 (Folder 3-5)
            - Follow-up questions, March 24-29 (Folder 6)
            - Transcript (Folder 7)
          - 1982 March 2. Udall Committee hearing, Jan. 28-March 4 (Folder 8)
          - 1982 March 3. Ottinger/Markey Committee hearing
            - General, Feb. 9-March 26 (Box 37., Folder 1)
            - Follow-up questions, Feb. 25-March 22. Includes extensive appendices (Folder 2-7)
            - Transcript (Box 38., Folder 1)
          - 1982 March 22. Bevill Committee hearing
            - General, Jan. 6-March 26 (Folder 2)
            - Follow-up questions, ca. March 26 (Folder 3)
          - 1982 March 24. Hatfield Committee hearing, March 24-April 16 (Folder 4)
        - FY 1984-1985
          - General
            - 1982 April-July (Folder 5-8)
            - 1982 July-1983 June (Box 39., Folder 1-6)
          - 1983 Feb. 22. Udall hearing
            - General
              - 1983 Jan.-Feb. (Folder 7)
              - 1983 Feb.-March (Box 40., Folder 1-2)
            - Follow-up questions (Folder 3-4)
            - Transcript (Folder 5)
          - 1983 March 10. Hart/Simpson hearing
            - General, Jan.-April (Folder 6-7)
            - Follow-up questions (Box 41., Folder 1-2)
            - Transcript (Folder 3)
          - 1983 March 17. Bevill hearing
            - General, 1982 Dec.-1983 March (Folder 4)
            - Follow-up questions (Folder 5-7)
            - Transcript (Folder 8)
          - 1983 March 22. Ottinger/Markey hearing
            - General, Feb.-March (Box 42., Folder 1)
            - Follow-up questions (Folder 2-5)
          - 1983 April 13. Hatfield Committee hearing, April-May (Folder 6-7)
          - 1983 June 8. Ottinger/Markey Committee hearing (Folder 8)
        - FY 1985
          - 1984 Feb. 9. Udall Committee hearing
            - General, Jan.-March (Box 43., Folder 1-3)
            - Transcript (Folder 4)
          - 1984 Feb. 23. Hart/Simpson Committee hearing
            - General, Feb.-May (Folder 5)
            - Follow-up questions (Folder 6-7)
            - Follow-up questions (contd.) (Box 44., Folder 1)
            - Transcript (Folder 2)
          - 1984 March 21. Hatfield Committee hearing, March-April (Folder 3-4)
          - 1984 March 22. Bevill Committee hearing
            - General, 1983 Dec.-1984 March (Folder 5)
            - Follow-up questions (Folder 6-7)
            - Follow-up questions (contd.) (Box 45., Folder 1-2)
            - Transcript (Folder 3)
        - FY 1985-1986
          - 1983 June-Aug. (Folder 4-8)
          - 1983 Sept.-1984 Jan. (Box 46., Folder 1-4)
        - FY 1986-1987, 1984 March (Folder 5)
    - Informational functions
      - General. Press releases, 1975-1978 (Folder 6-8)
      - Data processing, 1982-1983 (Box 47., Folder 1)
      - Document control
        - General. TERA Advanced Services Corp. contract for document control system, 1980 June-1982 Oct. (Folder 2-6)
        - Classification
          - General. Classification review reports, and reports of unaccounted for documents, 1976 June-1980 Feb. (Folder 7)
          - Guidelines. Relates to implementation of Executive Orders 11652 and 12065
            - 1975 April-1978 June (Folder 8-9)
            - 1978 July-1983 March (Box 48., Folder 1-2)
        - Freedom of Information Act/Sunshine Act
          - General. FOIA request, 1977 Nov. (Folder 3)
          - Common Cause litigation, 1981 Aug.-1982 Oct. (Folder 4-5)
    - Legal functions
      - General
        - General, 1982 Dec.-1983 May. Study Group on Organization of Legal Services (Folder 6)
        - Administrative Law Judges, 1981 March-1983 Dec. (Folder 7)
      - Office of the General Counsel
        - 1979 Oct.-1983 Jan. (Box 49., Folder 1-7)
    - Policy functions. Policy, Planning and Program Guidance (PPPG)
      - General
        - 1980 Dec.-1982 Nov. (Box 50., Folder 1-9)
        - 1982 Dec.-1984 Jan. (Box 51., Folder 1-4)
      - Reports
        - 1982 Year End Program Review, 1982 Oct.-1983 Jan. (Folder 5)
        - 1983 Mid-Year Program Review, 1983 April (Folder 6)
  - Notes, Daily Staff
    - 1983 June-July (Folder 7-8)
    - 1983 Aug.-Dec. (Box 52., Folder 1-3)
  - Reports
    - General
      - 1978 Nov. Office of Nuclear Regulatory Research (NRR), "Inquiry into Misconduct and Mismanagement in the Office of Nuclear Regulatory Research" (Folder 4)
      - 1979 Sept.-Oct. Office of Policy Evalution (OPE) and Office of the General Counsel (OGC), "Review of Delegation of Authority within NRC" (Folder 5)
      - 1981 March. Office of Inspector and Auditor (OIA), 1980 Annual Report (Folder 6)
      - 1981 May. "Summary Information Report." Includes organizational chart (Folder 7)
      - 1983 July. "NRC as an Executive Agency" (Folder 8)
    - General Accounting Office (GAO). Reports relating to the operation of the NRC as well as general issues of government administration
      - 1976 Jan.-March (Folder 9-10)
      - 1976 May-1978 Sept. (Box 53., Folder 1-9)
      - 1978 Oct.-1980 July. Includes "The NRC: More Agressive Leadership Needed," 1980 Jan. (Box 54., Folder 1-8)
      - 1980 Jan.-1981 Jan. (Box 55., Folder 1-5)
      - 1981 Feb.-1982 March. Includes "Improvements Needed in the NRC's Office of Inspector and Auditor," 1981 July (Box 56., Folder 1-8)
      - 1982 April-1983 April (Box 57., Folder 1-7)
      - 1983 May-1984 April (Box 58., Folder 1-4)
    - Secretary, Office of the (SECY Papers). Reports, memoranda, voting records and other miscellaneous administrative material, 1980-1983. NOTE: These materials cover the full range of topics included in this collection, but are organized here according to their administrative provenance. There are gaps in all the numbering sequences.
      - 1980
        - General
          - SECY 80-1 to 80-177 (Folder 5-10)
          - SECY 80-178 to 80-207 (Box 59., Folder 1-16)
          - SECY 80-208 to 80-230 (Box 60., Folder 1-18)
          - SECY 80-232 to 80-256 (Box 61., Folder 1-19)
          - SECY 80-257 to 80-281 (Box 62., Folder 1-14)
          - SECY 80-283 to 80-299 (Box 63., Folder 1-11)
          - SECY 80-301 to 80-324 (Box 64., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY 80-325 to 80-345 (Box 65., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY 80-346 to 80-367 (Box 66., Folder 1-11)
          - SECY 80-368 to SECY 80-373 (Box 67., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY 80-374 to SECY 80-391 (Box 68., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY 80-392 to SECY 80-421 (Box 69., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY 80-422 to SECY 80-440 (Box 70., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY 80-441 to SECY 80-464 (Box 71., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY 80-465 to SECY 80-485 (Box 72., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY 80-486 to SECY 80-505 (Box 73., Folder 1-8)
          - SECY 80-506 to SECY 80-527 (Box 74., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY 80-528 to SECY 80-550 (Box 75., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY 80-551 to SECY 80-555 (Box 76., Folder 1-4)
        - Commission review of Atomic Licensing Appeal Board (ALAB) decisions (SECY-A)
          - SECY A-80-1 to SECY A-80-7 (Folder 5-9)
          - SECY A-80-8 to SECY A-80-23 (Box 77., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY A-80-23 (contd.) to SECY A-80-40 (Box 78., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY A-80-41 to SECY A-80-50 (Box 79., Folder 1-9)
          - SECY A-80-51 to SECY A-80-71 (Box 80., Folder 1-11)
          - SECY A-80-72 to SECY A-80-98 (Box 81., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY A-80-99 to SECY A-80-123 (Box 82., Folder 1-11)
          - SECY A-80-124 to SECY A-80-150 (Box 83., Folder 1-10)
          - SECY A-80-151 to SECY A-80-183 (Box 84., Folder 1-12)
          - SECY A-80-184 to SECY A-80-204 (Box 85., Folder 1-4)
      - 1981
        - SECY 81-1 to SECY 81-13 (Folder 5-9)
        - SECY 81-14 to SECY 81-40 (Box 86., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-42 to SECY 81-55 (Box 87., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 81-56 to SECY 81-86 (Box 88., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-87 to SECY 81-114 (Box 89., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-116 to SECY 81-153 (Box 90., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-154 to SECY 81-187 (Box 91., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-188 TO SECY 81-219 (Box 92., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-220 to SECY 81-241 (Box 93., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-242 to SECY 81-284 (Box 94., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-286 to SECY 81-297 (Box 95., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 81-298 to SECY 81-319 (Box 96., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 81-320 to SECY 81-359 (Box 97., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 81-360 to SECY 81-382 (Box 98., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-383 to SECY 81-408 (Box 99., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-409 to SECY 81-427 (Box 100., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 81-428 to SECY 81-451 (Box 101., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-452 to SECY 81-484 (Box 102., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-485 to SECY 81-521 (Box 103., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 81-522 to SECY 81-557 (Box 104., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-558 to SECY 81-594 (Box 105., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-596 to SECY 81-603 (Box 106., Folder 1-11)
        - SECY 81-604 to SECY 81-627 (Box 107., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-628 to SECY 81-664 (Box 108., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-665 to SECY 81-699 (Box 109., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 81-700 to SECY 81-708 (Box 110., Folder 1-11)
      - 1982
        - SECY 82-2 to SECY 82-8
        - SECY 82-8 (contd.) to SECY 82-26 (Box 111., Folder 1-11)
        - SECY 82-27 to SECY 82-54 (Box 112., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 82-55 to SECY 82-76 (Box 113., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-77 to SECY 82-103 (Box 114., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-104 to SECY 82-127 (Box 115., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-128 to SECY 82-149 (Box 116., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-150 to SECY 82-168 (Box 117., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-169 to SECY 82-196 (Box 118., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-197 to SECY 82-204 (Box 119., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-205 to SECY 82-228 (Box 120., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-229 to SECY 82-258 (Box 121., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-259 to SECY 82-288 (Box 122., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-289 to SECY 82-305 (Box 123., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-306 to SECY 82-333 (Box 124., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 82-334 to SECY 82-364 (Box 125., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 82-365 to SECY 82-388 (Box 126., Folder 1-11)
        - SECY 82-389 to SECY 82-416 (Box 127., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 82-417 to SECY 82-444 (Box 128., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-445 to SECY 82-455 (Box 129., Folder 1-6)
        - SECY 82-456 to SECY 82-465 (Box 130., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 82-466 to SECY 82-496 (Box 131., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 82-497 to SECY 82-504 (Box 132., Folder 1-9)
      - 1983
        - SECY 83-1 to SECY 83-16
        - SECY 83-16 (contd.) to SECY 83-30 (Box 133., Folder 1-7)
        - SECY 83-31 to SECY 83-46 (Box 134., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-47 to SECY 83-59 (Box 135., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-59 (contd.) to SECY 83-62 (Box 136., Folder 1-7)
        - SECY 83-62 (contd.) to SECY 83-74 (Box 137., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-75 to SECY 83-97 (Box 138., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-98 to SECY 83-118 (Box 139., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-119 to SECY 83-142 (Box 140., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 83-143 to SECY 83-163 (Box 141., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-164 to SECY 83-176 (Box 142., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-177 to SECY 83-197 (Box 143., Folder 1-11)
        - SECY 83-198 to SECY 83-218 (Box 144., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 83-219 to SECY 83-231 (Box 145., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-232 to SECY 83-241 (Box 146., Folder 1-7)
        - SECY 83-242 to SECY 83-256 (Box 147., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-257 to SECY 83-278 (Box 148., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-279 to SECY 83-288 (Box 149., Folder 1-6)
        - SECY 83-290 to SECY 83-306 (Box 150., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-307 to SECY 83-327 (Box 151., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-328 to SECY 83-352 (Box 152., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-353 to SECY 83-369 (Box 153., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-370 to SECY 83-397 (Box 154., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-399 to SECY 83-418 (Box 155., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-419 to SECY 83-441 (Box 156., Folder 1-8)
        - SECY 83-442 to SECY 83-465 (Box 157., Folder 1-10)
        - SECY 83-466 to SECY 83-484 (Box 158., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-485 to SECY 83-504 (Box 159., Folder 1-9)
        - SECY 83-504 (contd.) to SECY 83-525 (Box 160., Folder 1-11)
- DOMESTIC NUCLEAR REACTOR LICENSING AND REGULATION, 1971-1984
  - General. Memoranda, letter, conference materials ("Environmental Licensing and Regulatory Requirements Affecting the Electric Utility Industry," 1978 Sept. 10-13, sponsored by the Edison Electric Institute/Envirosphere Company), reports, speech transcript
    - 1971-1978 (Box 161., Folder 1-6)
    - 1979-1982 (Box 162., Folder 1)
  - Atomic Safety and Licensing Board (ASLB) and Atomic Licensing Appeal Board (ALAB). Memoranda, 1979-1982 (Folder 2)
  - Intervenor funding. Reports, memoranda, printed articles, bills, notes, letters, 1975 July-1981 Aug. (Folder 3-7)
  - Licensing status. Reports, memoranda and charts relating to specific licensing actions, 1977-1984 (Box 163., Folder 1-3)
  - Regulatory reform. NOTE: For about 18 months after the TMI accident, licensing approvals were suspended while the NRC conducted internal reviews of licensing procedures (in accordance with the TMI Action Plan). Materials related to these internal reviews are included in the following "General" category. By early 1981, concern over the resultant licensing delays led to criticism and external pressure culminating in renewed legislative attempts to reform the regulatory process. Material related to these attempts has been organized under "Legislation", although some of it also relates to policy discussions continuing within the NRC.
    - General (Folder 4-6)
      - General. Post-TMI licensing policy
        - Licensing Policy Statement
          - General. Attachment to an unidentified document which summarized the major policy issues relating to expediting the licensing process
          - 1979 May-1980 Dec. (Box 164., Folder 1-8)
        - Pending construction permit/manufacturing licenses (CP/ML). Primarily policy issues relating to updated requirements for pending permits
          - 1980 Oct.-1981 Sept. (Box 165., Folder 1-8)
          - 1981 Oct.-1982 Jan. (Box 166., Folder 1-2)
      - 1973 Dec.-1978 May (Folder 3-8)
      - 1979 Jan.-1981 March. Includes a letter with attachments from Chairman Hendrie to Congressman Bevill, March 12 (Box 167., Folder 1-9)
      - 1981 March-May. Udall hearing, April 9 (Box 168., Folder 1-8)
      - 1981 May (Box 169., Folder 1)
      - 1981 June
        - General (Folder 2)
        - Moffett Committee hearing, June 18 (Folder 3-5)
      - 1981 July-Dec. Comments solicited by the NRC in response to a proposed rule to change the hearing process, 1981 July; and a memorandum from Chairman Palladino proposing the establishment of a task force to study regulatory reform, Sept. 21 (Folder 6-8)
      - 1982 Jan.-Sept. (Box 170., Folder 1-2)
      - 1984 March-June (Folder 3)
    - Legislation
      - General
        - Limited Work Authorizations (LWA), 1976 May-1977 Aug. (Folder 4)